so going back to our many core
challenges we have seen that there are
solutions to the increasing the on-chip
coherence traffic as the number of cores
grows we have seen solutions to the
increasing of chip traffic
as the number of cores grows and we have
also seen a way to have a directory that
will support our own chip network
and that solution was as we have
recently seen a distributed partial
directory which doesn't keep information
for every possible block in memory it
only keeps information
for a limited number of blocks and has a
replacement policy and invalidates
on-chip caches as a result of such
replacements
the next many core challenge we will
consider is that the power budget
available for the chip for example 100
watts that we can reasonably call from a
chip of the area that we can manufacture
is split among all the cores
so as the number of cores goes up
the power we can spend in each core goes
down
and that means
that the frequency and the voltage that
we can use
in each core goes down
and that means that if we have a single
threaded program it gets slower and
slower the more cores we have
because that single threaded program if
we only had one core would get the
power budget of the entire chip
with let's say 64 cores it gets only
a 64th part
of the power budget so what do we do
about this